ADITYA PRATAP

 $+91~704-429-6080 \diamond Hyderabad, India$ Email ♦ LinkedIn ♦ Github

OBJECTIVE

Dynamic and Proficient Front-End Developer with 5+ years of experience designing, building, and maintaining web applications, seeking full-time Front-end Developer. Have worked with multiple clients across various projects focusing on performance enhancement, responsive design and optimization

SKILLS

Programming Languages

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript

Libraries Testing tools React JS, React-Redux, Redux, Redux Toolkit, Next JS, React/Tanstack Query

Jest, React Testing Library, Cucumber, Cypress JS

WORK EXPERIENCE

FrontEnd Developer

Aug 2024 - Current Global Logic Hyderabad, IN

- Implemented the Next Gen Digital flow for client Verizon versus the existing Business as usual (BAU) flow Next Gen in a complete new tech stack - Next JS and Tanstack Query.
- Implemented E COM functionality for a user to keep shopping from the same point in the user journey after returning back within a time-span of 14 days using encrypted cookie.
- Reduced the max load time for the application to 2 secs.
- Worked on Page load optimization through Indexed DB approach to cater to multiple device load on the bundled screen to improved user experience.
- Delivered pixel perfect responsive design as per figma screens ensuring **improved user experience**.
- Lead a team of 5 developers from off shore towards successful and in time completion of assigned tasks, stories and defects.
- Worked pro actively with Backend Team in API design discussion and contract finalization to ensure reduced page load times as well as secured endpoints.
- Actively involved in code review process and code commit strategies.

Specialist Programmer

Jul 2018 - Aug 2024

Pune, IN

Infosys Limited

- Worked on the building design and development of subscription/retail product of a MAANG tech giant.
- Developed and implemented dynamic forms for the application, ensuring alignment with both business and technical requirements.
- Implemented common security patterns (e.g.: JWT) and performance patterns (e.g.: Lazy loading, **Pre-Loading**) to improve performance.
- Implemented access management (authorization) & user management for the application through common HOC design pattern.
- Streamlined application development process by introducing reusable components and custom hooks, resulting in decrease in time spent on bug fixes and maintenance tasks.
- Optimized core web vitals via **Lighthouse analysis**, culminating in a 20% reduction in application load time.
- Following Behavior Driven Development practices. Writing unit tests using Cucumber and Cypress and helping define the overall testing strategy to achieve approximately 90% code coverage
- Developed real time change of Feature Flags through dev tools to test various retailers on-the-go.

- Involved in technical analysis, UX discussion, User Interface design, API design discussions and collaborating with the backend team to develop integrations that are both secure and performant.
- Spearheaded building application dashboard while emphasizing **cross-browsers compatibility and a mobile-first approach.**
- Conducted extensive testing and debugging across multiple browsers (Chrome, Firefox, Safari, Edge) to ensure consistent functionality and visual fidelity.
- Designed and implemented responsive layouts and components using CSS3, Flexbox and media queries, ensuring seamless user experience across various devices and screen sizes.
- Optimized front-end performance through code refactoring, caching strategies, and performance profiling techniques, resulting in faster load times and smoother interactions.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science, West Bengal University of Technology, Kolkata YGPA - 8.25

2014-2018

CERTIFICATIONS

Front-End Certification (React) Hacker Rank - 07/2024 (See Certificate)

Front-End Expert Certification Algo Expert - 03/2023 (See Certificate)

ReactJS Certification Hacker Rank - 06/2022 (See Certificate)

JavaScript Certification Hacker Rank - 06/2022 (See Certificate)

Problem Solving Certification Hacker Rank - 05/2022 (See Certificate)

Product Developer Certification Crio.do - 03/2021 (See Certificate)

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Actively work on Front-end Repository on GitHub to help serve active seekers a one stop destination to cracking Front-end interviews
- Qualified in the top 2% of over 1000 applicants to move to a Power Programmer role within Infosys Ltd.
- Have been awarded Top Performer Award for consecutive quarters within Global Logic.